footprintnetwork.org 2019-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Global Footprint Network

Global Footprint Network respects the privacy of those who visit our websites. We know that donors have expressed extreme concern about the use of their personal information and the desire to have this information kept confidential. This Privacy Policy applies to the Global Footprint Network website www.footprintnetwork.org, to all associated subdomains, online services, and to those sites listed in the paragraph below labeled “Additional Websites Subject to the Privacy Policy.” By visiting any of the sites, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy. This policy describes our practices in connection with the information we collect on these sites, through our social media pages, and through email messages. If you disagree with any of the terms herein, please immediately discontinue use of the sites.

 **Donor Privacy Policy**

Global Footprint Network will not share or sell an online or offline donor’s personal information or giving information with anyone else, nor send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations. The information we collect is used to improve the content of our website and to notify visitors about news, special programs, offers, and other opportunities. The information is not shared with other organizations for commercial purposes. Note that this policy does not prohibit Global Footprint Network from contacting donors for informational, educational, or solicitation purposes.

 **Information We Collect**

When you visit the Global Footprint Network website, Global Footprint Network may collect personal information that you provide, such as your name, address, email address, and payment information. For instance, Global Footprint Network gathers information when you fill out the email newsletter signup form and donation form. We are GDPR compliant.

In addition, Global Footprint Network and its service providers use a variety of techniques to gather other information about your use of the sites, including, among other things, your IP address, browser type, mobile device type, content visited while on the sites, and the duration of your visit to the sites.

We use Google Analytics, which uses cookies and other, similar technologies to collect information about site use anonymously and reports website trends, without identifying individual visitors.

We also collect information about your interactions with email messages, such as the links clicked and whether the messages were opened or forwarded.

When Global Footprint Network developed its Footprint calculator at [www.footprintcalculator.org](http://www.footprintcalculator.org/) it made efforts to make it GDPR (EU General Data Protection Regulation) compliant.

We may share aggregate statistics and other non-personally identifiable information with third parties for marketing, advertising, research, or similar purposes. These aggregate statistics will not allow anyone to identify you.

 **Financial Transactions**

To process a charitable contribution, it is necessary for Global Footprint Network to gather the visitor’s name, email address, mailing address, phone, and credit card information. This data is used to verify identity and execute the financial transaction. Additionally, phone number and email address information may be used to contact visitors if there is a problem with the transaction.

 **Additional Websites Subject to the Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy shall apply to the following websites and all associated subdomains:  
• www.footprintcalculator.org  
• www.overshootday.org  
• data.footprintnetwork.org  
• www.footprintfinance.org  
• www.chinafootprintnetwork.org  
• www.achtung-schweiz.org

 **Questions/Contact Information**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or wish to opt out of receiving communications from us, please contact Global Footprint Network at [info@footprintnetwork.org](mailto:info@footprintnetwork.org). Please allow 10 business days for us to respond to your request.

 **Last updated:** May 9, 2019
